Finding Aid for Frank D. Beadle papers, 1951-1972.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Frank D. Beadle papers 1951-1972
Beadle, Frank D.,1899-
3 linear ft.
85745 Aa/2
Republican State Senator, 1951-1968, from St. Clair, Michigan, and member of the Senate Appropriations Committee. Scrapbooks of correspondence, newspaper clippings, and printed material detailing his political career; notebooks of speeches; papers relating to the proposed state income tax, 1962-1963; papers concerning the administration of the Blue Water Bridge, 1955-1963; and miscellanea.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Mr. Beadle (donor no. 5084 ) donated his papers to the library in several accessions, 1971-1977. 5084
The collection is open to research.
Republican State Senator, 1951-1968, from St. Clair, Michigan, and member of the Senate Appropriations Committee.
Scrapbooks documenting Beadle's career as a state legislator and politician, and as writer of doggerel poetry. The reocrds include correspondence, newspaper clippings, and printed material detailing his political career; notebooks of speeches; papers relating to the proposed state income tax, 1962-1963; papers concerning the administration of the Blue Water Bridge, 1955-1963; and miscellanea.
Subjects:
Blue Water Bridge (Port Huron, Mich. and Sarnia, Ont.); Bridges--Ontario.; Bridges--Michigan.; Michigan. Legislature.; Michigan--Politics and government--1946-1960.; Michigan--Politics and government--1961-1970.; Republican Party (Mich.); Saint Clair (Mich.); Taxation--Michigan.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-
Genre Terms:
Scrapbooks.
- Scrapbooks
  - Scrapbooks, 1951-1965, 9 volumes (Box 1)
  - Scrapbooks, 1966-1970, 5 volumes (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook concerning book of poetry, "Out of the Doggerel House" 1964-1965 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook concerning retirement announcement and testimonial dinner, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook concerning speech before the Michigan Association of School Boards, 1967 (Box 3)
- Other legislative files
  - Notebook containing congratulatory letters following stand on income tax and removal as caucus chairman, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Notebook concerning Michigan State University's Presidential Commission on Admission and Student Body Composition, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Notebook of speeches, 1959-1972 (Box 3)
  - Proposed state income tax, 1962-1963 (Box 3)
  - Apportionment law suit expenses, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Administration of the Blue Water Bridge, 1955-1963 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings and correspondence (Box 3)
  - Speech maaterial (include limericks and master of ceremonies material) (Box 3)
  - Speeches (Box 3)